<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
    <section name="The Basics">
        <item name="What is a Spell?"> A spell is a discrete magical effect, a single shaping of the magical energies that suffuse the multiverse into a specific, limited expression. In casting a spell, a character carefully plucks at the invisible strands of raw magic suffusing the world, pins them in place in a particular pattern, sets them vibrating in a specific way, and then releases them to unleash the desired effect - in most cases, all in the span of seconds. Spells can be versatile tools, weapons, or protective wards. They can deal damage or undo it, impose or remove conditions, drain life energy away, and restore life to the dead. Uncounted thousands of spells have been created over the course of the multiverse\'s history, and many of them are long forgotten. Some might yet lie recorded in crumbling spellbooks hidden in ancient ruins or trapped in the minds of dead gods. Or they might someday be reinvented by a character who has amassed enough power and wisdom to do so.
        </item>

        <item name="Spell Level"> Every spell has a level from 0 to 9. A spell\'s level is a general indicator of how powerful it is, with the lowly (but still impressive) &lt;i&gt;magic missile&lt;/i&gt; at 1st level and the earth-shaking &lt;i&gt;wish&lt;/i&gt; at 9th. Cantrips - simple but powerful spells that characters can cast almost by rote - are level 0. The higher a spell\'s level, the higher level a spellcaster must be to use that spell. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Spell level and character level don\'t correspond directly. Typically, a character has to be at least 17th level, not 9th level, to cast a 9th-level spell.
        </item>

        <item name="Known and Prepared Spells"> Before a spellcaster can use a spell, he or she must have the spell firmly fixed in mind, or must have access to the spell in a magic item. Members of a few classes, including bards and sorcerers, have a limited list of spells they know that are always fixed in mind. The same thing is true of many magic-using monsters. Other spellcasters, such as clerics and wizards, undergo a process of preparing spells. This process varies for different classes, as detailed in their descriptions.&lt;br/&gt; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;In every case, the number of spells a caster can have fixed in mind at any given time depends on the character\'s level.
        </item>
        
        <item name="The Schools of Magic"> Academies of magic group spells into eight categories called schools of magic. Scholars, particularly wizards, apply these categories to all spells, believing that all magic functions in essentially the same way, whether it derives from rigorous study or is bestowed by a deity. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The schools of magic help describe spells; they have no rules of their own, although some rules refer to the schools. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abjuration&lt;/b&gt; spells are protective in nature, though some of them have aggressive uses. They create magical barriers, negate harmful effects, harm trespassers, or banish creatures to other planes of existence. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conjuration&lt;/b&gt; spells involve the transportation of objects and creatures from one location to another. Some spells summon creatures or objects to the caster\'s side, whereas others allow the caster to teleport to another location. Some conjurations create objects or effects out of nothing. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Divination&lt;/b&gt; spells reveal information, whether in the form of secrets long forgotten, glimpses of the future, the locations of hidden things, the truth behind illusions, or visions of distant people or places. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enchantment&lt;/b&gt; spells affect  the minds of others, influencing or controlling their behavior. Such spells can make enemies see the caster as a friend, force creatures to take a course of action, or even control another creature like a puppet. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evocation&lt;/b&gt; spells manipulate magical energy to produce a desired effect. Some call up blasts of fire or lightning. Others channel positive energy to heal wounds. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Illusion&lt;/b&gt; spells deceive the senses or minds of others. They cause people to see things that are not there, to miss things that are there, to hear phantom noises, or to remember things that never happened. Some illusions create phantom images that any creature can see, but the most insidious illusions plant an image directly in the mind of a creature. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Necromancy&lt;/b&gt; spells manipulate the energies of life and death. Such spells can grant an extra reserve of life force, drain the life energy from another creature, create the undead, or even bring the dead back to life. Creating the undead through  the use of necromancy spells such as animate dead is not a good act, and only evil casters use such spells frequently. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Transmutation&lt;/b&gt; spells change the properties of a creature, object, or environment. They might turn an enemy into a harmless creature. bolster the strength of an ally, make an object move at the caster\'s command, or enhance a creature\'s innate healing abilities to rapidly recover from injury.
        </item>
        
        <item name="Spell Slots"> Regardless of how many spells a caster knows or prepares, he or she can cast only a limited number of spells before resting. Manipulating the fabric of magic and channeling its energy into even a simple spell is physically and mentally taxing, and higher-level spells are even more so. Thus, each spellcasting class\'s description (except that of the warlock) includes a table showing how many spell slots of each spell level a character can use at each character level. For example, the 3rd-level wizard Umara has four 1st-level spell slots and two 2nd-level slots. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;When a character casts a spell, he or she expends a slot of that spell\'s level or higher, effectively "filling" a slot with the spell. You can think of a spell slot as a groove of a certain size - small for a 1st-level slot, larger for a spell of higher level. A 1st-level spell fits into a slot of any size, but a 9th-level spell fits only in a 9th-level slot. So when Umara casts magic missile, a 1st-level spell, she spends one of her four 1st-level slots and has three remaining. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Finishing a long rest restores any expended spell slots (see chapter 8 for the rules on resting). &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Some characters and monsters have special abilities that let them cast spells without using spell slots. For example, a monk who follows the Way of the Four Elements, a warlock who chooses certain eldritch invocations, and a pit fiend from the Nine Hells can all cast spells in such a way. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CASTING A SPELL AT A HIGHER LEVEL&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;When a spellcaster casts a spell using a slot that is of a higher level than the spell, the spell assumes the higher level for that casting. For instance, if Umara casts magic missile using one of her 2nd-level slots, that magic missile is 2nd level. Effectively, the spell expands to fill the slot it is put into. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Some spells, such as magic missile and cure wounds, have more powerful effects when cast at a higher level, as detailed in a spell\'s description.
        </item>
        
        <item name="Cantrips"> A cantrip is a spell that can be cast at will, without using a spell slot and without being prepared in advance. Repeated practice has fixed the spell in the caster\'s mind and infused the caster with the magic needed to produce the effect over and over. A cantrip\'s spell level is 0.
        </item>
        
        <item name="Rituals"> Certain spells have a special tag: ritual. Such a spell can be cast following the normal rules for spellcasting, or the spell can be cast as a ritual. The ritual version of a spell takes 10 minutes longer to cast than normal. It also doesn\'t expend a spell slot, which means the ritual version of a spell can\'t be cast at a higher level. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;To cast a spell as a ritual, a spellcaster must have a feature that grants the ability to do so. The cleric and the druid, for example, have such a feature. The caster must also have the spell prepared or on his or her list of spells known, unless the character\'s ritual feature specifies otherwise, as the wizard\'s does.
        </item>
        
        <item name="The Weave of Magic"> The worlds within the D&amp;D multiverse are magical places. All existence is suffused with magical power, and potential energy lies untapped in every rock, stream, and living creature, and even in the air itself. Raw magic is the stuff of creation, the mute and mindless will of existence, permeating every bit of matter and present in every manifestation of energy throughout the multiverse. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Mortals can\'t directly shape this raw magic. Instead, they make use of a fabric of magic, a kind of interface between the will of a spellcaster and the stuff of raw magic. The spellcasters of the Forgotten Realms call it the Weave and recognize its essence as the goddess Mystra, but casters have varied ways of naming and visualizing this interface. Say any name, without the Weave, raw magic is locked away and inaccessible; the most powerful archmage can\'t light a candle with magic in an area where the Weave has been torn. But surrounded by the Weave, a spellcaster can shape lightning to blast foes, transport hundreds of miles in the blink of an eye, or even reverse death itself. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;All magic depends on the Weave, though different kinds of magic access it in a variety of ways. The spells of wizards, warlocks, sorcerers, and bards are commonly called &lt;b&gt;arcane     magic&lt;/b&gt;. These spells rely on an understanding - learned or intuitive - of the workings of the Weave. The caster plucks directly at the strands of the Weave to create the desired effect. Eldritch knights and arcane tricksters also use arcane magic.  the spells of derics, druids, paladins, and rangers are called &lt;b&gt;divine magic&lt;/b&gt;. These spellcasters\' access to the Weave is mediated by divine power - gods, the divine forces of nature, or the sacred weight of a paladin\'s oath. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Whenever a magic effect is created, the threads of the Weave intertwine, twist, and fold to make the effect possible. When characters use divination spells such as &lt;i&gt;detect magic&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;identify&lt;/i&gt;, they glimpse the Weave. A spell such as &lt;i&gt;dispel magic&lt;/i&gt; smooths the Weave. Spells such as &lt;i&gt;antimagic field&lt;/i&gt; rearrange the Weave so that magic flows around, rather than through, the area affected by the spell. And in places where the Weave is damaged or torn, magic works in unpredictable ways - or not at all.
        </item>
    </section>
    
    <section name="Casting a Spell">
        
        <item name="Casting Time"> Most spells require a single action to cast, but some spells require a bonus action, a reaction, or much more time to cast. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;BONUS ACTION&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;A spell cast with a bonus action is especially swift. You must use a bonus action on your turn to cast the spell, provided that you haven\'t already taken a bonus action this turn. You can\'t cast another spell during the same turn, except for a cantrip with a casting time of 1 action. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;REACTIONS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Some spells can be cast as reactions. These spells take a fraction of a second to bring about and are cast in response to some event. If a spell can be cast as a reaction, the spell description tells you exactly when you can do so. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;LONGER CASTING TIMES&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Certain spells (including spells cast as rituals) require more time to cast: minutes or even hours. When you cast a spell with a casting time longer than a single action or reaction, you must spend your action each turn casting the spell, and you must maintain your concentration while you do so (see "Concentration" below). If your concentration is broken, the spell fails, but you don\'t expend a spell slot. If you want to try casting the spell again, you must start over.
        </item>

        <item name="Range"> The target of a spell must be within the spell\'s range. For a spell like &lt;i&gt;magic missile&lt;/i&gt;, the target is a creature. For a spell like &lt;i&gt;fireball&lt;/i&gt;, the target is the point in space where the ball of fire erupts. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Most spells have ranges expressed in feet. Some spells can target only a creature (including you) that you touch. Other spells. such as the shield spell, affect only you. These spells have a range of self. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Spells that create cones or lines of effect that originate from you also have a range of self, indicating that the origin point of the spell\'s effect must be you (see "Areas of Effect"). &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Once a spell is cast, its effects aren\'t limited by its range, unless the spell\'s description says otherwise.
        </item>

        <item name="Components"> A spell\'s components are the physical requirements you must meet in order to cast it. Each spell\'s description indicates whether it requires verbal (V), somatic (S), or material (M) components. If you can\'t provide one or more of a spell\'s components, you are unable to cast the spell. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;VERBAL (V)&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Most spells require the chanting of mystic words. The words themselves aren\'t the source of the spell\'s power; rather, the particular combination of sounds, with specific pitch and resonance, sets the threads of magic in motion. Thus, a character who is gagged or in an area of silence, such as one created by the silence spell, can\'t cast a spell with a verbal component. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SOMATIC (S)&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Spellcasting gestures might include a forceful gesticulation or an intricate set of gestures. If a spell requires a somatic component, the caster must have free use of at least one hand to perform these gestures. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;MATERIAL (M)&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Casting some spells requires particular objects, specified in parentheses in the component entry. &lt;br/&gt;A character can use a component pouch or a spellcasting focus (found in chapter 5) in place of the components specified for a spell. But if a cost is indicated for a component, a character must have that specific component before he or she can cast the spell. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;If a spell states that a material component is consumed by the spell, the caster must provide this component for each casting of the spell. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A spellcaster must have a hand free to access these components, but it can be the same hand that he or she uses to perform somatic components.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;ROYALTY (R)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Jim Darkmagic\'s unique brand of spellcasting mixes arcane expertise with a particular kind of pecuniary fervor. New spells originally developed by Jim spawned a new type of spell component, which has since spread to other spells created by employees and franchisees of Acquisitions Incorporated: the royalty component. &lt;br/&gt;To cast a spell that employs a royalty component (including using a spell scroll or other magic item that stores such a spell), a caster must have sufficient funds on their person. The cost of the casting is set by the caster who creates the spell, but is typically 1 gp per spell slot level. When the spell is cast, the royalty is magically transported to a coffer or other object designated by the creating spellcaster. This payment is made whether the caster using the spell is aware of the royalty component or not. If the caster does not have sufficient funds, the spell is not lost but it cannot be cast.&lt;br/&gt;Though many casters have tried to circumvent the royalty component, none have ever fully succeeded. However, it is said that a character can attempt a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) check while casting a spell with a royalty component. With a successful check, the payment is taken from a random creature within 10 feet of the caster, without that creature\'s knowledge.
        </item>

        <item name="Duration"> A spell\'s duration is the length of time the spell persists. A duration can be expressed in rounds, minutes, hours, or even years. Some spells specify that their effects last until the spells are dispelled or destroyed. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;INSTANTANEOUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Many spells are instantaneous. The spell harms, heals, creates, or alters a creature or an object in a way that can\'t be dispelled, because its magic exists only for an instant. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CONCENTRATION&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Some spells require you to maintain concentration in order to keep their magic active. If you lose concentration, such a spell ends. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;If a spell must be maintained with concentration, that fact appears in its Duration entry, and the spell specifies how long you can concentrate on it. You can end concentration at any time (no action required). &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Normal activity, such as moving and attacking, doesn\'t interfere with concentration. The following factors can break concentration: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#8226; Casting another spell that requires concentration.&lt;/b&gt; You lose concentration on a spell if you cast another spell that requires concentration. You can\'t concentrate on two spells at once. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#8226; Taking damage.&lt;/b&gt; Whenever you take damage while you are concentrating on a spell, you must make a Constitution saving throw to maintain your concentration. The DC equals 10 or half the damage you take, whichever number is higher. If you take damage from multiple sources, such as an arrow and a dragon\'s breath, you make a separate saving throw for each source of damage. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#8226; Being incapacitated or killed.&lt;/b&gt; You lose concentration on a spell if you are incapacitated or if you die. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The DM might also decide that certain environmental phenomena, such as a wave crashing over you while you\'re on a storm-tossed ship, require you to succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration on a spell.
        </item>

        <item name="Targets"> A typical spell requires you to pick one or more targets to be affected by the spell\'s magic. A spell\'s description tells you whether the spell targets creatures, objects, or a point of origin for an area of effect (described below). &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Unless a spell has a perceptible effect, a creature might not know it was targeted by a spell at all. An effect like crackling lightning is obvious, but a more subtle effect, such as an attempt to read a creature\'s thoughts, typically goes unnoticed, unless a spell says otherwise. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;A CLEAR PATH TO THE TARGET&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;To target something, you must have a cleor path to it, so it can\'t be behind total cover. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;If you place an area of effect at a point that you can\'t see and an obstruction. such as a wall, is between you and that point, the point of origin comes into being on the near side of that obstruction. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;TARGETING YOURSELF&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;If a spell targets a creature of your choice, you can choose yourself, unless the creature must be hostile or specifically a creature other than you. lf you are in the area of effect of a spell you cast, you can target yourself.
        </item>

        <item name="Areas of Effect"> Spells such as &lt;i&gt;burning hands&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;cone of cold&lt;/i&gt; cover an area, allowing them to affect multiple creatures at once. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A spell\'s description specifies its area af effect, which typically has ane of five different shapes: cone, cube, cylinder, line, or sphere. Every area of effect has a &lt;b&gt;point of origin&lt;/b&gt;, a location from which the spell\'s energy erupts. The roles for each shape specify how you position its point of origin. Typically, a point of origin is a point in space, but some spells have an area whose origin is a creature or an object. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A spell\'s effect expands in straight lines from the point of origin. If no unblocked straight line extends from the point of origin to a location within the area of effect, that location isn\'t included in the spell\'s area. To block one of these imaginary lines, an obstruction must provide total cover. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CONE&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;A cone extends in a direction you choose from its point of origin. A cone\'s width at a given point along its length is equal to that point\'s distance from the point of origin. A cone\'s area of effect specifies its maximum length. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A cone\'s point of origin is not included in the cone\'s area of effect, unless you decide otherwise. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CUBE&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You select a cube\'s point of origin, which lies anywhere on a face of the cubic effect. The cube\'s size is expressed as the length of each side. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A cube\'s point of origin is not included in the cube\'s area of effect, unless you decide otherwise. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CYLINDER&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;A cylinder\'s point of origin is the center of a circle of a particular radius, as given in the spell description. The circle must either be on the ground or at the height of the spell effect. The energy in a cylinder expands in straight lines from the point of origin to the perimeter of the circle, forming the base of the cylinder. The spell\'s effect then shoots up from the base or down from the top, to a distance equal to the height of the cylinder. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A cylinder\'s point of origin is included in the cylinder\'s area of effect. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;LINE&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;A line extends from its point of origin in a straight path up to its length and covers an area defined by its width. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A line\'s point of origin is not included in the line\'s area of effect, unless you decide otherwise. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPHERE&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You select a sphere\'s point of origin, and the sphere extends outward from that point. The sphere\'s size is expressed as a radius in feet that extends from the point. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;A sphere\'s point of origin is included in the sphere\'s area of effect.
        </item>

        <item name="Saving Throws"> Many spells specify that a target can make a saving throw to avoid some or all of a spell\'s effects. The spell specifies the ability that the target uses for the save and what happens on a success or failure. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The DC to resist one of your spells equals 8 + your spellcasting ability modifier + your proficiency bonus + any special modifiers.
        </item>

        <item name="Attack Rolls"> Some spells require the caster to make an attack roll to determine whether the spell effect hits the intended target. Your attack bonus with a spell attack equals your spellcasting ability modifier + your proficiency bonus. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Most spells that require attack rolls involve ranged attacks. Remember that you have disadvantage on a ranged attack roll if you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature that can see you and that isn\'t incapacitated.
        </item>

        <item name="Combining Magical Effects"> The effects of different spells add together while the durations of those spells overlap. The effects of the same spell cast multiple times don\'t combine, however. Instead, the most potent effect - such as the highest bonus - from those castings applies while their durations overlap. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if two clerics cast bless on the same target, that character gains the spell\'s benefit only once; he or she doesn\'t get to roll two bonus dice.
        </item>

        <item name="Casting in Armor"> Because of the mental focus and precise gestures required for spellcasting, you must be proficient with the armor you are wearing to cast a spell. You are otherwise too distracted and physically hampered by your armor for spellcasting.
        </item>
        
    </section>

    <section name="Caster Classes">
        
        <item name="Artificer">&lt;b&gt;MAGICAL TINKERING&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;1st-level artificer feature&lt;/i&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;You\'ve learned how to invest a spark of magic into
            mundane objects. To use this ability, you must have
            thieves\' tools or artisan\'s tools in hand. You then
            touch a Tiny nonmagical object as an action and
            give it one of the following magical properties of
            your choice:
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;• The object sheds bright light in a 5-foot radius and
            dim light for an additional 5 feet.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;• Whenever tapped by a creature, the object emits a
            recorded message that can be heard up to 10 feet
            away. You utter the message when you bestow this
            property on the object, and the recording can be
            no more than 6 seconds long.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;• The object continuously emits your choice of an
            odor or a nonverbal sound (wind, waves, chirping,
            or the like). The chosen phenomenon is perceivable up to 10 feet away.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;• A static visual effect appears on one of the object\'s
            surfaces. This effect can be a picture, up to 25
            words of text, lines and shapes, or a mixture of
            these elements, as you like.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The chosen property lasts indefinitely. As an
            action, you can touch the object and end the property early.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can bestow magic on multiple objects,
            touching one object each time you use this feature,
            though a single object can only bear one property
            at a time. The maximum number of objects you
            can affect with this feature at one time is equal to
            your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one object). If you try to exceed your maximum, the oldest
            property immediately ends, and then the new property applies.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;THE MAGIC OF ARTIFICE&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;As an artificer, you use tools when you cast your
            spells. When describing your spellcasting, think about
            how you\'re using a tool. For example, if you cast &lt;i&gt;cure
            wounds&lt;/i&gt; using alchemist\'s supplies, you could be
            quickly producing a salve. If you cast it using tinker\'s
            tools, you might have a miniature mechanical spider
            that binds wounds. The effect of the spell is the same
            either way.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Such details don\'t limit you in any way or provide you
            with any benefit beyond the spell\'s effects. You don\'t
            have to justify how you\'re using tools to cast a spell.
            But describing your spellcasting creatively is a fun way
            to distinguish yourself from other spellcasters.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;1st-level artificer feature&lt;/i&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;You\'ve studied the workings of magic and how to
            cast spells, channeling the magic through objects.
            To observers, you don\'t appear to be casting spells
            in a conventional way; you appear to produce
            wonders from mundane items and outlandish
            inventions.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;TOOLS REQUIRED&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;You produce your artificer spell effects through your
            tools. You must have a spellcasting focus - specifically
            thieves\' tools or some kind of artisan\'s tool-in
            hand when you cast any spell with this Spellcasting
            feature (meaning the spell has an "M" component
            when you cast it). You must be proficient with the
            tool to use it in this way. See the equipment chapter
            in the Player\'s Handbook for descriptions of these tools.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;After you gain the Infuse Item feature at 2nd level,
            you can also use any item bearing one of your infusions
            as a spellcasting focus.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS (0-LEVEL SPELLS)&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;You know two cantrips of your choice from the artificer spell list.
            At higher levels, you learn additional
            artificer cantrips of your choice, as shown in the
            Cantrips Known column of the Artificer table.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;When you gain a level in this class, you can replace one
            of the artificer cantrips you know with
            another cantrip from the artificer spell list.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The Artificer table shows how many spell slots you
            have to cast your artificer spells. To cast one of your
            artificer spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain
            all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You prepare the list of artificer spells that are
            available for you to cast, choosing from the artificer
            spell list. When you do so, choose a number of artificer spells equal to your Intelligence modifier + half
            your artificer level, rounded down (minimum of one
            spell). The spells must be of a level for which you
            have spell slots.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you are a 5th-level artificer, you
            have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots.
            With an Intelligence of 14, your list of prepared
            spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in
            any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell
            cure wounds, you can cast it using a lst-level or a
            2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t remove it
            from your list of prepared spells.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can change your list of prepared spells when
            you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of artificer spells
            requires time spent tinkering with your
            spellcasting focuses: at least 1 minute per spell level
            for each spell on your list.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your
            artificer spells; your understanding of the theory behind
            magic allows you to wield these spells with superior
            skill. You use your Intelligence whenever an artificer
            spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition,
            you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the
            saving throw DC for an artificer spell you cast and
            when making an attack roll with one.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;RITUAL CASTING&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can cast an artificer spell as a ritual if that spell
            has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;INFUSE ITEM&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;2nd-level artificer feature&lt;/i&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You\'ve gained the ability to imbue mundane items
            with certain magical infusions, turning those objects into magic items.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;INFUSIONS KNOWN&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;When you gain this feature, pick four artificer infusions to learn,
            choosing from the "Artificer Infusions" section at the end of the class\'s description.
            You learn additional infusions of your choice when
            you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in
            the Infusions Known column of the Artificer table.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace
            one of the artificer infusions you learned with a new one.
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;INFUSING ITEMS&lt;/b&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch a
            nonmagical object and imbue it with one of your
            artificer infusions, turning it into a magic item. An
            infusion works on only certain kinds of objects, as
            specified in the infusion\'s description. If the item requires attunement,
            you can attune yourself to it the
            instant you infuse the item. If you decide to attune to
            the item later, you must do so using the normal process for
            attunement (see the attunement rules in the &lt;i&gt;Dungeon Master\'s Guide&lt;/i&gt;).
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Your infusion remains in an item indefinitely, but
            when you die, the infusion vanishes after a number
            of days equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1 day). The infusion also vanishes if you
            replace your knowledge of the infusion.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can infuse more than one nonmagical object
            at the end of a long rest; the maximum number of
            objects appears in the Infused Items column of the
            Artificer table. You must touch each of the objects,
            and each of your infusions can be in only one object
            at a time. Moreover, no object can bear more than
            one of your infusions at a time. If you try to exceed
            your maximum number of infusions, the oldest infusion ends, and then the new infusion applies.
            &lt;br&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;If an infusion ends on an item that contains other
            things, like a &lt;i&gt;bag of holding&lt;/i&gt;, its contents harmlessly
            appear in and around its space.
            
        </item>

        <item name="Bard"> You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you can tune to different situations. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the bard spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You know two cantrips of your choice from the bard spell list. You learn additional bard cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Bard table. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELL SLOTS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Bard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells. you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level ar higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you know the 1st-level spell cure wounds and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast cure wounds using either slot. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the bard spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The Spells Known column of the Bard table shows when you learn more bard spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the table. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;RITUAL CASTING&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can use a musical instrument (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.
        </item>

        <item name="Cleric"> As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the cleric spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn additional cleric cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Cleric table. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t remove it from your list of prepared spells. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;RITUAL CASTING&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt; You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt; You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.
        </item>

        <item name="Druid"> Drawing on the divine essence of nature itself, you can cast spells to shape that essence to your will. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the druid spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the druid spelllist. You learn additional druid cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Druid table. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you are a 3rd-level druid, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots, With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st ar 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the lst.level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t remove it from your list of prepared spells, &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;RITUAL CASTING&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells.
        </item>

        <item name="Paladin"> By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t remove it from your list of prepared spells. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.
        </item>

        <item name="Ranger"> By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELL SLOTS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The Spells Known column of the Ranger table shows when you learn more ranger spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
        </item>

        <item name="Sorcerer"> An event in your past, or in the life of a parent or ancestor, left an indelible mark on you, infusing you with arcane magic. This font of magic, whatever its origin, fuels your spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the sorcerer spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;At 1st level, you know four cantrips of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. You learn additional sorcerer cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Sorcerer table. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELL SLOTS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Sorcerer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these sorcerer spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you know the 1st-level spell &lt;i&gt;burning hands&lt;/i&gt; and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast &lt;i&gt;burning hands&lt;/i&gt; using either slot. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The Spells Known column of the Sorcerer table shows when you learn more sorcerer spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the sorcerer spells you know and replace it with another spell from the sorcerer spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your sorcerer spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition. you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a sorcerer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;\&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your sorcerer spells.
        </item>

        <item name="Warlock"> &lt;b&gt;OTHERWORLDLY PATRON&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;At 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice: the Archfey,  the Fiend, or the Great Old One, each of which is detailed at  the end of the class description, Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;PACT MAGIC&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Your arcane research and the magic bestowed on you by your patron have given you facility with spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the warlock spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn additional warlock cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in  the Cantrips Known column of the Warlock table. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELL SLOTS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Warlock table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast  the 1st-level spell &lt;i&gt;thunderwave&lt;/i&gt;, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The Spells Known column of the Warlock table shows when you learn more warlock spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what\'s shown in the table\'s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Charisma whenever a spell refers lo your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when selling  the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.
        </item>

        <item name="Wizard"> As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power, See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. &lt;b&gt;CANTRIPS&lt;/b&gt;  At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Wizard table. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLBOOK&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Wizard table shows how many spell slots you have to east your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For example, if you\'re a 3rd-level wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination, chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell magic missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting  the spell doesn\'t remove it from your list of prepared spells. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING ABILITY&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell save DC&lt;/b&gt; = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&lt;b&gt;Spell attack modifier&lt;/b&gt; = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;RITUAL CASTING&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don\'t need to have the spell prepared. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPELLCASTING FOCUS&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;LEARNING SPELLS OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook (see the "Your Spellbook" sidebar). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;YOUR SPELLBOOK&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The spells that you add to your spellbook as you gain levels reflect the arcane research you conduct on your own, as well as intellectual breakthroughs you have had about the nature of the multiverse. You might find other spells during your adventures. You could discover a spell recorded on a scroll in an evil wizard\'s chest, for example, or in a dusty tome in an ancient library. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Copying a Spell into the Book.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; When you find a wizard spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your spellbook if it is of a level for which you have spell slots and if you can spare the time to decipher and copy it. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Copying a spell into your spellbook involves reproducing the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique system of notation used by the wizard who wrote it. You must practice the spell until you understand the sounds or gestures required, then transcribe it into your spellbook using your own notation. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp. The cost represents material components you expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your other spells. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Replacing the Book.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; You can copy a spell from your own spellbook into another book - for example, if you want to make a backup copy of your spellbook. This is just like copying a new spell into your spellbook, but faster and easier, since you understand your own notation and already know how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 10 gp for each level of the copied spell. &lt;br/&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;If you lose your spellbook, you can use the same procedure to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new spellbook. Filling out the remainder of your spellbook requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this reason, many wizards keep backup spellbooks in a safe place. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Book\'s Appearance.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Your spellbook is a unique compilation of spells, with its own decorative flourishes and margin notes. It might be a plain, functional leather volume that you received as a gift from your master, a finely bound gilt-edged tome you found in an ancient library, or even a loose collection of notes scrounged together after you lost your previous spellbook in a mishap.
        </item>
    </section>
</root>
