<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
    <section name="v_2_11_0">
        <item name="title">Version 2.11 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated to include spells from the following sourcebooks:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; Acquisitions Incorporated&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; Explorer\'s Guide to Wildemount&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; Lost Laboratory of Kwalish&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; Rime of the Frostmaiden
        </item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_2_12_0">
        <item name="title">Version 2.12 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated to include spells from &lt;b&gt;Fizban\'s Treasury of Dragons&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Typos and minor errors in several spells have been corrected.
        </item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_2_13_0">
        <item name="title">Version 2.13 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated to include spells from &lt;b&gt;Strixhaven: A Curriculum of Chaos&lt;/b&gt;.
        </item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_2_13_1">
        <item name="title">Version 2.13.1 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated to include spells from the
            &lt;b&gt;Astral Adventurer\'s Guide&lt;/b&gt;.
            </item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_0_0">
        <item name="title">Version 3.0.0 update</item>
        <item name="description">This update adds the ability to keep track of spell slots for each character.</item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_1_0">
        <item name="title">Version 3.1.0 update</item>
        <item name="description">This update adds a button to the spell slots screen to regain all slots.</item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_4_0">
        <item name="title">Version 3.4.0 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated with the following new features:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; The ability to filter spells by royalty has been added.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; The count for each spell list is now shown next to the list name in both the side menu and the bottom navigation bar.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Additionally, this update fixes some typos and mistakes in the text for a few spells.</item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_5_0">
        <item name="title">Version 3.5.0 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated with the following new features:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; Content from &lt;b&gt;The Book of Many Things&lt;/b&gt; has been added&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; The higher level text for &lt;b&gt;Erupting Earth&lt;/b&gt; has been corrected&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#8226; The spellcasting information has been updated with a description of the royalty component.</item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_6_0">
        <item name="title">Version 3.6.0 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated to include spells from the &lt;b&gt;2024 Player\'s Handbook&lt;/b&gt;. As many of the spells from this book are new versions of those from previous sourcebooks, this update also adds an option to &lt;b&gt;hide duplicate spells&lt;/b&gt; between the 2024 PHB and previous sourcebooks. Toggling this option off will allow both versions to be shown in the spell list. If this option is enabled, one can choose whether they prefer to see &lt;b&gt;2024 or 2014&lt;/b&gt; versions of the spells. This setting can be adjusted on a &lt;b&gt;character-by-character basis&lt;/b&gt;.</item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_6_3">
        <item name="title">Version 3.6.3 update</item>
        <item name="description">This release updates the text of spells that were affected by the errata for Xanathar's Guide to Everything.</item>
    </section>
    <section name="v_3_7_0">
        <item name="title">Version 3.7.0 update</item>
        <item name="description">The spellbook has been updated to include the spell from the &lt;b&gt;Guildmaster's Guide to Ravnica&lt;/b&gt;. This update also corrects the &lt;b&gt;duration of Transmute Rock&lt;/b&gt;.</item>
    </section>
</root>
